[
{"question":"1. Mass spectrum gives valuable information about:",
"answers":{
            "a":"molecular mass",
            "b":"functionals groups",
            "c":"conjugation",
            "d":"vibrational states "
          },
"correctAnswer":"a"},

{"question":"2. The ions are separated based on their mass to charge ratios in",
"answers":{
            "a":"ionsiation chamber",
            "b":"mass analyzer",
            "c":"sample inlet",
            "d":"detector"
          },
"correctAnswer":"c"},

{"question":"3. The typical ionisation energy used in a EI-MS is:",
"answers":{
            "a":"0.7 eV",
            "b":"7 eV",
            "c":"70 eV",
            "d":"700 e V"
          },
"correctAnswer":"a"},

{"question":"4. Mass spectrum is a plot of:",
"answers":{
            "a":"relative intensity vs mass-to-charge",
            "b":"relative intensity vs mass-to-energy",
            "c":"voltage vs mass-to-charge",
            "d":"voltage vs mass -to -energy"
          },
"correctAnswer":"c"},

{"question":"5. The molecular ion peak in a mass spectrum corresponds to:",
"answers":{
            "a":"ion formed by fragmentation of a molecule",
            "b":"molecule losing an electron to form a radical cation",
            "c":"the most abundant ion",
            "d":"ion with smallest mass-to-charge"
          },
"correctAnswer":"a"},

{"question":"6. The base peak in a mass spectrum corresponds to:",
"answers":{
            "a":"ion formed by fragmentation of a molecule",
            "b":"molecule losing an electron to form a radical cation",
            "c":"the most abundant ion",
            "d":"ion with smallest mass-to-charge"
          },
"correctAnswer":"c"},

{"question":"7. In an magnetic sector mass analyser, the ion separation is based on:",
"answers":{
            "a":"ions with the correct mass-to-charge ratio undergo stable oscillation and passes through the cylinderal rods before they hit the detector",
            "b":"lighter ions have higher velocity",
            "c":"greater mass to charge ratio have larger radius of the curved path",
            "d":"Heavier ions have higher velocity"
          },
"correctAnswer":"a"},

{"question":"8. The sample introduced into the sample inlet first gets:",
"answers":{
            "a":"vapourised",
            "b":"ionised",
            "c":"accelarated",
            "d":"deflected"
          },
"correctAnswer":"c"},

{"question":"9. If a compound has an even number of nitrogen atoms, its molecular ion will appear at an even mass value. This is called:",
"answers":{
            "a":"Mass rule",
            "b":"Molecular ion rule",
            "c":"Nitrogen rule",
            "d":"Stevenson's rule"
          },
"correctAnswer":"a"},

{"question":"10. The most probable fragmentation is the onw that leaves the positive charge on the fragment with the lowest ionsiation energy. This rule is called:",
"answers":{
            "a":"Mass rule",
            "b":"Molecular ion rule",
            "c":"Nitrogen rule",
            "d":"Stevenson's rule"
          },
"correctAnswer":"c"}
 
]
